Finding Aid for E.A. Densmore General Store (Dansville, Mich.) records, 1857-1953
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
E.A. Densmore General Store (Dansville, Mich.) records 1857-1953
E.A. Densmore General Store (Dansville, Mich.)
14 volumes (in 1 box) and 2 oversize volumes
851033 Bb.2 2; BB.2 Outsize
Dansville, Michigan, general store. Ledgers, daybooks, cash books, and other business records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were the gift of Mrs. Edward E. Lofberg (donor no. 4028 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The E.A. Densmore General Store was located in Dansville, Michigan, in Ingham County.
The record group includes business day books, ledgers, cashbooks, stock purchases and inventories, and collection books. Some of the records were maintained by E. Rice. It is not clear if these were accounts for a separate firm or whether these were earlier records for a predecessor general store.
Subjects:
Business records.; Dansville (Mich.); General stores--Michigan--Dansville.; Ingham County (Mich.)
Contributors:
Densmore, Ernest Albert.
- Business records
  - Sales record, 1857 (Box 1)
  - Stock inventories, 1863 (Box 1)
  - Day book (E. Rice), 1866-1867 (Box 1)
  - Day book (Rice and Cobb), 1869 (Box 1)
  - Day book (E. Rice), 1869-1873 (Box 1)
  - Disbursements, 1888-1891 (Box 1)
  - Stock purchase and inventory, 1892-1895 (Box 1)
  - Ledger, 1893-1895 (Box 1)
  - Collections book, 1894-1900 (Box 1)
  - Ledger, 1899-1901 (Box 2)
  - Cash book, 1912 (Box 2)
  - Receipts and accounts, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Ledger, 1915-1946 (Box 2)
  - Records of legal fees collected, 1933-1953 (Box 2)
  - Collections book, 1894-1903 (Volume 1)
    (outsize volume)
  - Cashbook, 1910-1913 (Volume 2)
Related Material
The library also has a small collection of Densmore family materials. This includes a farm account book of Thad Densmore, 1876-1880; a day book, 1880-1892; the University of Michigan law thesis of Ernest Albert Densmore, 1902; and a short history of the Densmore and Rice families.